蜀山是中國西面巴蜀一帶群山的統稱
Mount Zu was the collective name for the mountain chain in ancient Zu in Western China.
也就是現在四川
It is also the Sichuan of today.
巴蜀在古代軍事戰略上
Mount Zu was of great military strategic
是扮演著一個非常重要的角色
importance in ancient China.
古語說,天下未亂蜀先亂
As such,it was constantly in a state of war,
天下已治蜀未治
regardless of reign and dynasty.
野史以及民間小說裡的巴蜀
But in Chinese legends and folklore,
有它另外神秘的一面
Mount Zu was also a place of mystique.
原因是山中多奇峰古剎
For it harbored numerous exotic peaks and old temples
所以相傳有創仙,俠聖
from which many legends were born.
也都構成了蜀山劍俠的傳奇
This was where our story,"Zu,Warriors from the Magic Mountain" began.
時為五胡亂華末期
It was in the 5th century,
十一國並立,列強爭霸,天下大亂
China has been suffering from decades of civil wars and unrest.
給我傳探子,快點
Get me the scout immediately!
探子,狄明奇見左統領右統領
Scout Ti Ming-Chi reporting to 1st and 2nd Commanders.
黃旗敗兵現在在哪裡?
Where are the Yellow Troops now?
報告左統領,東蜀敗軍黃旗兵
Reporting to 1st Commander.
旗倒兵散,亡命奔逃
The Yellow Troops have been defeated and fled in disarray.
屬下探知,他們已經到飛來峰下三丈澗了
They have now made it down to San-Chang Creek.
太好了,我們就在水路打得他們屍沉江底
That"s wonderful!We"ll take to the waters to finish our attack.
報告左統領,黃旗兵潰不成軍
Soldiers of the Yellow Troops are already wounded and in disarray.
三丈澗附近一帶有很多平民
Moreover,any attack will hurt
揮軍直往會傷及無辜
the many civilians along San-Chang Creek.
既然這樣我們就走陸路好了
Then we will go after them on land.
你立即前往探路,我一定叫他們全軍覆沒
You may lead the way.I want not a soul to be spared!
小兵遵命
Yes,Commander!
走陸路迂迴曲折,冒險太大
The land route meanders and is too dangerous.
狄明奇,立即帶路
Ti Ming-Chi,lead the way by water!
我們要由水路追截,走水路 不行
Let"s go by the water.No way.
走水路時間太慢,敵人會趁機逃走
The waters take too long and will give the enemy an opportunity to retreat.
還是由陸路追截,走陸路
We"d better go by land!
混帳,走水路 走陸路
Nonsense!Go by water!Go by land.
走水路
By water!
狄明奇,你聽誰的話?
Ti,whose orders do you obey?
小兵兩個都聽
I obey both your orders.
兩個都聽就是違抗軍令,我殺了你
That"s insubordination!L"ll kill you!
那我兩個都不聽
Then I will obey neither one of your orders!
也殺
That"s worse!Kill him!
殺
Kill him!
兩位統領,我不是這個意思
My two Commanders,that"s not what I meant!
別打了,自己人
Stop!I am not the enemy!
有船?
Kill...Kill...
船家,送我過江
A boat?Get me across the river.
不行
I can"t.
為什麼?
Why not?
後邊有把刀說不行
The sword behind me says no.
船家,閃開
Move aside!
西蜀兵 東蜀兵?
- West Zu soldier? - East Zu soldier?
西蜀兵,這兒水靜河飛,不是打仗的地方
West Zu soldier,this is not a battlefield.
對,你先收刀
You"re right.Then put away your sword.
為什麼你不先收?你先收
You put away yours first.No.You first!
我收後
After you!
兩位兄台,你們也不用爭了
Gentlemen,no need to fight over this.
我數三聲,你們即刻分開收刀
L"ll count to three,and you"ll both put away your swords.
就這麼說,預備
Ready...Set...
你又說不行了
Hey,I thought you said we"re not going to fight!
我五代同堂
Four generations of my ancestors were killed by East Zu soldiers.
四代給東蜀兵殺了,我要幫他們報仇
I have to avenge their deaths.
你還說吶,我們家六代同堂
So?Your soldiers killed five generations of my ancestors!
就是被你們西蜀兵殺的,這怎麼算?
How should I figure those lives?
怎麼算?拿把刀來算
Fine.Let the sword do us justice.
我的命硬過這把刀,怎麼算我都不怕
Fine.L"m not afraid of you.
我斬...
L"ll slash you...
我擋...
l"ll Block...
我斬...我擋...
I slash...Block...
斬...擋...
I slash,slash,slash...I block,block,block...
斬,斬 擋
I slash,slash...I block...
你慘了,我的救兵來了
Bad news for you.My reinforcements are here.
怎知道是你們的人?是我們的人不行嗎?
How do you know they"re yours?May be they"re mine.
那容易,看箭是什麼顏色不就行了
That"s easy enough.Just take a look at the color of the arrow.
你拿枝來看看
Get one and see for yourself.
這次真是我的救兵來了
They"re really my reinforcements.
你還沒拿進來,怎麼知道箭是什麼顏色?
How could you know?You didn"t even get an arrow in here.
不用拿了,摸得出是什麼顏色了
No need.I could tell by my touch.
你不信?你去看看
You don"t believe me?Take a look yourself.
你先看看
You take a look first.
兩邊都不是
They"re for neither one of us.
是黃色的...
They"re yellow!
船頭還是船尾?船尾
Front or rear of the boat?Rear!
抓他們上來
Get them out of the water!
是
Yes!
不用怕,這幾年打仗打得我累死了
Don"t you worry.L"m tired from fighting all these years.
不想再跟你打了,我走了
I won"t fight you anymore.L"m leaving.
我不打了
I won"t fight...
都說不打了,不打了...
I said I won"t fight you anymore...
你的水壺
Your water bottle!
真是我的水壺
It is my water bottle!
你沒事吧?
Are you all right?
你這麼大個子,膽子這麼小
You are so big,but such a timid cat!
你還說呢,咱們剛認識不久
Hey,we just met.
不知道你是好人還是壞人
I didn"t know if you"re a good or bad guy.
對了,你是什麼地方人?
By the way,where are you from?
我是南安東界三里鋪左邊那條村的
L"m from the village on the left side of Nan-An.
是嗎?我也是那邊的人
Really?We"re practically neighbors!
不過我是右邊那條村的
L"m from the village on the right!
難怪這麼臉熟
No wonder your face looked so familiar.
你這人還不錯
You"re not such a bad guy!
當然不錯,除了衣服顏色不同,還不是人
We"re both good men.We"re just dressed in different colors.
現在天下大亂,就因為國不為民民不屬國
That"s the crux of our problem.The country is so divided.
現在咱們在這兒聊天
We can chat so nicely here.
如果在戰場上怎麼能辦得到呢
But if we were on the battlefield...
殺...
Charge...
又來了
Not again!
沖...
Charge!
殺...上...
七彩繽紛,簡直彩色大混戰
This sure is a colorful battle!
別管什麼顏色打起來,看不出來的
Forget about the colors.Let"s pretend to fight.No one will notice!
你怎麼玩真的?
Are you for real?
假裝打,別認真的
Just fake it!Don"t fight so hard!
我們究竟還打不打?
Should we carry on?
你顧前,我顧後,找機會溜
You watch the front,I mind the back.First chance we get,we slip away.
那就來了
Let"s get going then!
別表演了,快走吧
Stop showing off.Let"s go!
死鬼,這麼大的力?
Ouch!Why did you hit me so hard?
有反應
Nice reaction!
胖子,我在這兒
Chubby,l"m over here!
別怕,讓我來幫你
Don"t worry!Let me help you!
我們三個打一個
Three against one.
我弄錯了,自己人,動他
We"re on the same side.Get him!Get him!
我們六個打三個
Six against three...
還不追
Get them!
我們九個打六個
Nine against six!
我們一起打他一個
All of us against him!
殺...
Charge...
快走
Run!
我們裝死吧
Let"s pretend we"re dead!
我們不要動手,讓他們打個夠吧
Just let them fight it out.
不知道他們打到什麼時候?
Wonder when they"ll be through?
我看差不多了
Not too long,I hope.
你們也裝死的嗎?
You guys are pretending too?
就剩下黃的了,我們趕快走
Oh,it"s the Yellows again!
還有一個紅衣服,一個藍衣服
There"s still the Red and the Blue.
別讓他們跑了,快追
Don"t let them get away.
追...
Go after them!
你先走,快點,我在這兒擋著
You go on ahead.L"ll divert them here.
不行,我們生死之交把你留下太不夠義氣
No way.We"re friends!I can"t leave you here like this!
傻小子,死一個都死好,快走
One alive is better than two dead!Run!
不走 走吧
No!Go!
誰推你下去的?
Who pushed you off?
娘親,救命
Mommy!Help!
恩人留步,救命恩人
Swordsman!My Savior!Please don"t go so soon.
你有事跟我說嗎?
You have something to say to me?
大俠,你一定知天下正處於水深火熱之中
Swordsman,you must know the world is plagued with war and destruction.
現在兵荒馬亂,生靈塗炭
With your remarkable kung-fu and abilities,
大俠你武功蓋世,一定要打救世人
you must rescue us from this plight.
天下蒼生,十一國並立
Wars and unrest are perpetual
自古以來經常都在過動盪不安的生活
throughout the history of men.
但是歸根結底,咎由自取
But the troubles were all caused by men
互相殘殺,視人命為草介
who kill each other and have no respect for human lives whatsoever.
簡直是不知所謂
Woe onto them!
就算你跟我在一起,也無法改變
There"s nothing you or I can change.
人心已經敗壞
You should go into seclusion in the mountains
你應該趁尚有良知進入深山避世去吧
while you can still tell right from wrong.
大俠何必這麼說呢
Please do not give up,Master.
只要人人盡力天下一定能夠太平的
If everyone can give their best,peace will come.
真是後生可畏,還教訓起我來了
So you"re lecturing me now!
最可惜是時不予你
But l"m afraid this is just not your time.
你再不離開這裡,就會變成跟他們一樣
If you do not leave now,you will become one of them!
大俠...
Swordsman!Swordsman!
大俠
Swordsman!
大俠都是神出鬼沒的
All legendary swordsmen come and go in mysterious ways.
他現在在試我,好,我就等到他為止
He"s testing me now.Fine.L"ll wait for him right here.
我終於等到你來了
L"ve finally waited for you to show!
等我?你太傻了
That was a very foolish thing to do in a hell like this.
這兒這麼危險,閻羅王才等你
This is so danger here.Hell will be waiting for you.
閻羅王?對了,難怪這兒這麼多骷髏頭
Hell?That"s why all the skulls are here!
一定是曾經打過仗
This must have been a battleground.
不是打過仗,這些骷髏頭都雕了魔教標誌
No.All the skulls bear the sign of the Evil Disciples.
他們為了修煉邪術不惜犧牲這麼多小孩子
To train their evil sorcery,the Evil Disciples needed bones of virgins.
這些都是童子骨
These children were the sacrifice.
童子骨?
Bones of virgins?
你現在知道為什麼我要你離開吧
Now you know why I wanted you to get out of here.
是不是因為我是童子?
Is it because l"m still a virgin?
還好
Thank God!
你錯了,無論你是不是童子
You"re wrong.It doesn"t matter whether you are or not.
那些邪魔妖道絕對不會放過你的
The Evil Disciples will not let you live.
況且你還自認童子,根本沒人相信
Besides,no one will believe you"re a virgin anyway!
怎麼樣?你為什麼在這兒等我?
So,why were you waiting for me?
我想你收我做徒弟
I want to be your student.
我一向是獨來獨往
L"ve always been a loner.
你這個壞習慣不能改嗎?
Then change your bad habit as of today!
師父...
Teacher...Teacher...Teacher!
我不是你師父
L"m not your teacher.
你教我武功
If you teach me how to fight,
我學成之後可以鋤強扶弱,普救世上
I will help the meek and fight the bad.
我不會收你做徒弟的
I will not take you as my student.
師父...
Teacher...Teacher...
再叫我就無影無蹤了
Keep calling me and l"ll vanish.
我不叫了,你快現身吧
All right.L"ll shut up.Please come out!
是血鴉
Lt"s the Blood crows!
出鞘
Unsheathe!
九重天上顯星辰
Stars shine in seventh heavens.
一輪明月罩乾坤
The moon lights up the earth.
魔...
Evil...Evil...
不用摸了,自己人
Calm yourself.They"re on our side.
崑崙藏曉如
Hsiao-Yu of Kun-Lun.
南海是丁引
Ting-Yin of Nan-Hai.
丁引
Ting-Yin.
曉如禪師
Abbott Hsiao-Yu.
原來你姓丁 關你什麼事?
So your name is Ting!Lt"s none of your business!
書生,十年期到了,也是長眉約你來的?
Lt"s been ten years!Did Long Brows ask you to come too?
和尚,你怕你難以應付叫我助你一臂之力
Monk,he asked me to lend you a hand.
兩支烏鴉這麼大驚小怪
Just a couple of Blood crows had you rattled.
你怎麼對付血魔的護法?
How can you handle the Blood Demon?
我呸,阿彌陀你佛
Damn you.Praise Buddha!
血魔日益猖狂,我們聯手才是上策
The Blood Demon is increasingly out of control.It"s best that we team up.
你說怎麼樣?
What do you say,Monk?
出家人慈悲為懷,普度眾生
My mission is to save all humanity.
魔教在石林古剎作惡
The Evil Disciples have been carrying on
所以佛都有火,何況我曉如?
their evil deeds out of the Old Temple.
三年來我跟我的蠢徒弟出入青藏
For three years,my dumb student and
就是追查他們的下落
I have tried to track them down.
想不到在這兒碰到你
We never thought we"d run into you here.
這兒妖氣這麼重
It seems to me there are more than
看來不止幾個妖道這麼簡單
a few of them lurking here.
你說怎麼辦?
What do you think we should do?
你多此一問
Don"t ask.
我一向的作風是同桌吃飯各自修行
My motto is we may share a table but I work alone.
你走你的路 真是死性不改
You are on your own.Monk,you haven"t changed a bit!
我行我素,各走各路
Just stay out of my way!
一真 師父
Yi-Chen!Teacher!
童子 大俠
Virgin Boy!Master Ting.
我們入古剎 是
Let"s go into the Old Temple.Okay.
入古剎
Into the Old Temple!
這個和尚是什麼人?
Who"s that monk?
他是一個最衝動的人,朋友
He"s a most impulsive man.Hey,my friend...
童子
Virgin Boy!
叫我?
Are you calling me?
你想不想進去看看?好
Would you like to get a glimpse inside?Yes.
一真過來
Yi-Chen,come here!
是,師父
Yes,Teacher!
臭書生,走開,我沒空顧你了
Get away,Bookworm!I can"t take care of you too!
短毛和尚,顧你自己吧
You watch out for yourself.
吃素吃得多了,手沒力了
Vegetarians have no strength.
阿彌陀佛,我呸
Damn you!Praise Buddha!
師父
Teacher.
小心
Be careful!
走
Come on.
魔教護法,歡迎貴客
The Evil Disciples welcome their valuable guests.
你怎麼會在這兒?
Hey,how did you get over here?
彫蟲小技,瞧著吧
That"s nothing.Just watch the show.
和尚,這兒這麼危險,你下來幹什麼?
Monk,you shouldn"t have come down here.It"s very dangerous.
你不激我,我也會下來幫你
You don"t have to say that.I would"ve helped you anyway.
你們是何方貴客,敢闖入魔教教壇
Who dares to trespass the Evil Disciple"s alter?
我們是明知山有虎,偏向虎山行
Who else but the most bold
一定不是泛泛之輩
and daring!
今天是替天行道
We are here today to destroy the root of all evil!
他們是什麼人
Who are these characters?
他們是奸的,我們是忠的,明白嗎?
They"re the bad guys,we"re the good guys.Understand?
我魔教教規,替天行道者殺 殺...
To those who destroy evil,We kill!
守正辟邪者殺 殺...
To the righteous who shun evil,We kill!
普度眾生者殺 殺...
To those who save humanity,We kill!
逆我魔教者殺 殺...
To all against us,We kill!
他們還有什麼人不殺?
Is there anyone they spare?
順我者,不殺
To those who obey us,we spare!
和尚,你以為能說服他們
Monk,do you think you can
今天晚上我們就不用動手了嗎?
talk your way out of a fight today?
你還是留點氣,等會兒用吧
You"d better save your energy to do battle later.
對,臭書生,今天讓我替你留個全屍吧
That"s right,Bookworm.L"ll let you die in one piece!
潑水...潑滅它
Water!Use water to put it out!
真厲害,吃不消了
That"s too much!I can"t take it!
和尚,要不要幫忙?
Monk,do you need a hand?
回鞘
Sheathe!
你還不走?
Hey!What are you waiting for?
想不到奔波多年,始終是功虧一簣
Our years of hard work have proven to be futile!
大師,都怪我不好,如果不是我...
It was all my fault,Abbott.If I hadn"t...
小兄弟,你也不用難過了
Don"t feel bad,young man.
不錯,小施主
That"s right.
今天你能夠過大難總算是天降福緣
It"s a blessing that you"re still alive.
和尚,什麼時候我們又天降福緣再見面
Monk,when will I be blessed to see you again?
天降福緣沒你的份,我們以後最好別見面
No blessing for you!Let"s not meet again.
今天要不是你那些妖道根本就不會溜掉
If it weren"t for you,the evil doers wouldn"t have gotten away!
你真是語無倫次,不知所謂
Don"t talking nonsense.
好,既然是這樣,天南地北任你挑
Fine!If that"s the way you feel North,South,East,West.Pick a direction.
今日太陰在位,我向北走
Yin is strong today.I will head north.
那我向南走
Then I will head south.
好從此之後
Good!From this day on,
我們就後會無期...
may our paths never cross again!!
阿彌陀你個佛
Praise Buddha!
一真 是
Yi Chen!Yes!
走
Let"s go!
小卒子,你保重,我們今後會有期了
Take care,Soldier.L"ll see you around.
大俠...
Swordsman...Swordsman...
Swordsman!
又失蹤了,根本不聽我的話
He has vanished again.Never bothered to hear a word I said.
叫你們搭救世人,你們一聲不響就走了
I urged you to save the world and you disappeared without a trace!
你們學了一身功夫有什麼用?
What"s the use of knowing kung-fu?
全都是縮頭烏龜
You are all cowards!
難怪天下大亂,妖孽橫生
No wonder evil and calamity have taken over the world!
還說人家咎自由取,你們也有責任
You said men have brought it upon themselves,but you are responsible too!
天大地大我最大,我不用靠你們靠我自己
L"ll take charge then.I don"t need any of you.I will manage all on my own!
你們以後別再回來
Don"t ever come back again!!
你們回來了
You"re back!
都說後會無期了,又在這兒見面了
We said we"d never meet again!Why have our paths crossed?
說明了你向北我向南的
You said you were heading north and me heading south!
轉了方向也不說一聲,現在說有什麼用?
Why did you change direction?
還說,我們的武器已經給他們吸住了
Stop the nonsense!He"s sucked away our weapons.
快想辦法吧
Do something!
什麼事?
What is happening?
不知道,我跟師父這麼多年
L"m not sure.But all these years,
從來沒見過他這麼緊張的
l"ve never seen my Teacher so nervous.
那邊怎麼樣?
What"s going on out there?
出鞘
Unsheathe!
大師 師父...
Monk!Teacher!
回鞘
Sheathe!
走
Let"s go!
和尚
Hey,Monk.
我們從來沒合作過,想不到一合作就出事
We never worked together and the first time we do,it"s a disaster!
你別說話
Just don"t talk!
你幹什麼的你?
What are you doing?
我運真氣給你
L"m transfusing energy into you!
大敵當前,你開什麼玩笑
This is no time for practical jokes!
玩笑?你讓我笑也笑不出來
Jokes?I don"t find it funny at all!
一真,你師伯發神經了
Yi-Chen,your teacher is losing his mind!
不要讓他這樣做
Don"t let him do it!
一真 師父
Yi-Chen!Teacher!
叫他別這樣做 師伯
Tell him to stop!Master Ting.
現在不治你師父,他的性命就危險了
Your teacher"s condition is critical.I must do this to save him!
師父 師父說的話你聽不聽
Teacher!Are you disobeying your Teacher?
師伯
Master Ting!
傻小子,跪來跪去幹什麼
Stop this nonsense!
快點跟這位小兄弟出去看看
Stand guard with this young brother outside!
如果有什麼事馬上叫我
Holler if you see anything!
丁引
Ting,
血魔會趁機會偷襲我們的
you fool!Blood Demon will take this opportunity to attack us!
一真
Yi-Chen!
出去
Go outside!
回來
Come back!
出去
Go outside!
回來
Come back!
出去
Go outside!!
一真和尚哪兒去了?
Where did Yi-Chen go?
千萬不要出來
You"d better not show yourself!
又有貴人幫我,不可能,我這麼倒霉
Someone came to my rescue again?That"s impossible.
怎麼會黏上的?
How did these get stuck to me?
這些是什麼?
What are these?
你究竟是誰?
Who are you?
我就是峨嵋開山老祖,長眉
I am Long Brows,founder of the Ou-Mei Clan!
峨嵋開山老祖,你在這兒幹什麼?
Founder of Ou-Mei Clan,what are you doing here?
這種場面怎麼能沒有我呢?
I wouldn"t have missed this for the world!
你是忠是奸?
Are you a good guy or bad?
當然是忠的
Good,of course!
奸的怎麼會白衣服的,你看清楚
Do bad guys wear white?Look closer!
別碰我的鬍子?
Don"t pull my beard!
我怎麼會黏過來的?
What do I do?
別碰我的鬍子?
I said not to pull my beard!
那現在怎麼辦?
Now what?
不要動
D-o-n"-t touch!!
小子
Hey,kid.
你叫我?
Are you calling me?
難道是叫我自己,撿兩塊石頭 是
Of course.Pick two rocks.
大塊點
Bigger ones!
跟我來
Follow me.
我叫你扔就扔,我沒叫你扔,你千萬別扔
Throw only when I tell you.
你們這些所謂正道人士,根基未深
You so-called righteous ones are vulnerable and weak.
所以讓我血魔趁虛而入
You"ve left an opening for me,the Blood Demon.
這個和尚中了我血魔的毒
This Monk has been poisoned by my venom.
在十天之內,他就會毒血攻心走火入魔
Within ten days,the venom will travel to his heart.
那到個時候他就會成為我血魔的替身
And then he"ll become the Blood Demon"s double.
這就叫做道高一尺,魔高一丈
Just remember.Evil is deadlier than righteous.
那是什麼玩意?
What is that?
血魔元神出竅
His soul"s exodus.
元神出竅是什麼?
Exodus?What do you mean?
血魔形體雖然打散了
Even though I have destroyed his body.
元神未滅
His soul still lives.
拿童子骨來保護自己
He uses virgin skulls to protect himself
過些日子,找機會復活
and waits for the chance to resurrect.
捉住我的腳
Grab my feet!
我的浩天鏡也無法徹底除掉他
Even my Sky Mirror cannot destroy his soul.
這次可背鍋了
We"re in trouble this time.
鍋?誰背鍋了?
Who can control him then?
暫時還是我背,我的浩天鏡還可以鎮壓他
For now,my Sky Mirror can subdue him.
不過七七四十九天之後
But when the Big Dipper
天上北斗七星移位
begins to shift in 49 days,
到時候我浩天鏡就會十年一次黯然無光
my Sky Mirror will lose its shine
威力全無
and will be rendered powerless.
那怎麼辦?
What will happen then?
那時候由你背了
Then it"ll be up to you.
我來背?
Me?
不是你背,難道還是我背?
Yes!Who else?
你有聽說過沒有,長江後浪推前浪
Lt"s time for the next generation to take over.
峨嵋開山有兩把劍
Ou-Mei had two exceptional swords,
一把紫郢劍,一把青索劍
Purple and Green,
人稱紫青雙劍
known as the Twin Swords.
十八年前女神李亦奇
18 years ago Girl Wonder,Li l-Chi,
帶了這兩把劍去天外天洞內洞苦修
took them to Cave Beyond to study.
現在只要拿到這兩把劍就可消滅這元神
Only these two swords can destroy the Blood Demon"s soul.
那天外天洞內洞怎麼去?
How do you get to Cave Beyond?
天外天洞內洞的入口在天刀峰
It is on Heaven"s Blade Peak.
現在你即刻起程
You must go now.
如果遲了被他出了竅
Once the exodus takes place,
到時候集天下三仙二老一子七僧的法力
then nothing in this world will be
也沒有辦法了
able to stop the Blood Demon.
你聽到了沒有?
Did you hear me?
那你呢?
What about you?
你傻的,如果我去了誰來對付他?快去
Don"t be silly.I have to stay to control him.Now go!
還不快去
What are you waiting for?
師父
Teacher!
崑崙第十八代弟子一真,跪下接令
Kun-Lun"s 18th generation disciple,Yi-Chen.Kneel down!
從現在開始你就是崑崙派第十八代掌門人
You are now the 18th Chief of the Kun-Lun Clan!
接令
Take the order.
這一串是崑崙掌門法珠
These are the Chief's beads.
一真,你要記住
Yi Chen!Remember,as Chief,
身為掌門要負起一門的責任
you are responsible for the entire Clan.
要承先繼後耀我崑崙
And for bringing glory to Kun-Lun!
師父,你可別看不開
Teacher,don"t do it!
你不要管我
Don"t mind me!
我這樣怎麼做掌門人?
How can I be the Chief like this?
那塊石頭呢?
Where"s the rock?
師父
Teacher!
你認為你封了經脈就可以自殺了嗎?
You think you can just kill yourself?
我要治好你 我不讓你治
I will find someone to cure you!I don"t want you to!
I want to!I don"t want you to!
不要吵
Shut up!
你剛才跟誰說話?
Who were you talking to just now?
我是掌門人,我不准...
I am the Chief,I...
師父,我不是有意的,我把它穿起來好了
l"m sorry,Teacher.I didn"t mean to.L"ll restring it.
想不到這個世界亂成這樣
The world is in more disarray than I thought.
本來我想求你們搭救我們凡夫俗子的
I had originally asked you to save us mortals.
現在不知道誰救誰
Now I really can"t tell who is saving who.
今天七七四十九天的第一天
Today is the first day of the 49 days.
讓我帶這個和尚去治好了病
Let me get this Monk cured first.
然後我立刻去找紫青雙劍,希望還來得及
Then l"ll go after the Twin Swords before time runs out.
那是什麼東西?
What is it?
有魚了
Fish.
下面很有勁 是嗎
It"s great down there!Really?
還走...
Still trying to run?
那條魚戲弄我
Darn it.
你這死魚
You bad fish!
電鰻
Lt"s charged!
小卒子,它還很有氣
Soldier,l"ve got the fish here!
小和尚
Little Monk.
什麼事?
What?
吃過沒有?我以前也做過幾天和尚的
Have you ever had fish?I was once a monk for a few days.
那大師說吃熟的魚就不算殺生的,試試吧
I was told that eating cooked fish is not considered killing.Want some?
真的不算殺生?
Are you sure?
不算
Positive!
師伯
Master Ting.
這不是師父,這是血魔的替身
That"s not Master Ting!That"s the Blood Demon"s double!
那把劍呢?
Where"s that sword?
在你後面
Right behind you!
那個是真的那個是假的?
Which one is real and which is the double?
怎麼變成女的了?
He"s turned into a woman!
回鞘
Sheathe!
邪魔妖孽無孔不入,你們要小心知道嗎?
Evil is omnipresent.Be careful!
知道
Yes.
一真,什麼東西?
What is that?
是魚,我剛剛抓住
Lt"s a fish.
想把它放生,積點陰德
I was just about to free it.Have mercy on all living things!
如果沒事,我們去瑤池仙堡
We"d better get going to the Fort.
幸虧師伯不知道魚是熟的,還給你
Good thing he didn"t know the fish was cooked!Take it back.
幾位可以請回
You may all leave.
這位大師中的毒我無法醫治
I cannot cure this Monk.
望聞問切,是斷症四大基要
You didn"t even diagnose him.
你不聞不問,怎麼知道無法醫治呢?
How do you know you cannot cure him?
你錯了,除非是我們堡主出關
Only the Countess can cure him.
堡主?
Countess?
原來你們還有一位堡主
We didn"t know you have a Countess.
我們堡主閉關多年
The Countess has been in seclusion for years.
你們想她出關,除非...
She"ll not come out and cure him,unless...
除非什麼?
Unless what?
除非是有緣人
Unless he is sent by Fate.
仙堡冰焰每天燃燒一次
Our Fort Flame burns once everyday,
燃燒的時間有時長有時短
sometimes long,sometimes short.
在冰焰熄滅之前
During this period of time,
凡病人見到堡主
if she comes out,
堡主必定悉力以赴治好他
the Countess will heal anyone who comes for help.
現在冰焰將盡,我們的堡主還沒出現
The Flame is about to burn out and the Countess has not shown yet.
看來各位並非是有緣之人
Looks like it is fate that the Monk does not get treated.
那...我師父怎麼辦?
Then what happens to my Teacher?
國有國法,家有家規
The Fort has its rules.
既然我們身在仙堡,就要尊重仙堡的規矩
Now that we"re here,we must abide by its rules.
我丁引以一身元氣,務令冰焰長燃
I,Ting-Yin,will sustain the flame
縱使全身化為烏有,我丁引也在所不惜
even if it takes all the forces out of my body!
我們有言在先
I thought we had agreed
一切的事聽命天地間一個緣字
to trust everything to fate!
是,我現在要做的就是阻止你的制做孽緣
Yes,that"s why l"m trying to stop you from creating ill fate!
不是那個妖女嗎?
Hey,there"s that witch!
我們中計了
We"ve been trapped!
小卒子...
Soldier...Soldier...Soldier!
師伯
Master Ting.
你不能見了女人都叫妖女
Don"tjust call every woman you see a witch!
師伯,不是
No,Master Ting.
不是什麼?
What do you mean "no"?
那個堡主明明是妖女的樣子
She really looked like the witch we saw!
你才是妖女
You are witch.
聽泉台的妖道用移形遁光法騙你們
That was evil disguised as the Countess.
你們上當了
You"ve been fooled.
你要打醒十二精神
Now you stand guard.
現在我要給他開任督二脈
I have to bring his veins into unison.
打通任督二脈,那不是傳授武功給他
Bring his veins into unison?That"s like teaching him how to fight!
他應該謝謝你才對
He has you to thank for that.
師父...
Teacher...Teacher.
大俠
Master Ting.
不要出聲,現在我跟你一氣相連
Not a sound!L"m transfusing energy into you.
稍有不慎,你我兩個人經脈都會盡毀
Any mishap,both our veins will be shot and we"ll die.
那我怎麼辦?
What should I do?
普神合一,意如流水
Concentrate and let your will guide you.
這麼踩師父怎麼修道嗎?
That"s no way to treat a monk!
我這麼厲害
L"ve turned into a super man!
你這麼做,是什麼意思嗎?
Why are you doing this?
難道你不想治好這個和尚嗎?
Don"t you want to save this monk?
冷不冷嗎?很冷
Are you cold?Very.
那班丫鬟站在門口,我們怎樣到裡面去看
How can we get passed these girls to get inside?
你們看什麼?
Hey!What are you staring at?
這麼凶,很難說服她們讓我們進去了
What a temper!It doesn"t look like they"ll let us through.
不知道有沒有別的進口
I wonder if there is another entrance.
這兒這麼大當然有,我們找找看
L"m sure there is one in here!Let"s look for it!
你們想幹什麼?
Hey!What are you doing?
沒什麼,小妹妹,我們想找個地方解個手
Nothing.We just need to use the toilet,sister.
行不行嗎?不行
Can we?You can"t!
仙堡之內外人不可以亂闖亂撞
Strangers may not wander around in the Fort!
沒關係,急起來到處都是茅房
That"s all right.We"ll just do it right here.
你敢?
Don"t you dare!
不敢
No?
你儘管試試
I dare you!
試一試?試就試,怕什麼?
All right.You said it!
你以為這樣就可以嚇唬我了嗎?
You think that will scare me?
幹麼你這麼狠?
You are too much!
千萬別告訴我師父
Better not tell my Teacher!
曉如
Hsiao-Yu!
堡主閉關三年,一出關就消耗很多真氣
The healing has exhausted
所以需要休息
the Countess and she needs her rest.
現在和尚的毒已經解了
The monk"s venom has been dissolved.
請你們別再打擾堡主,請
The two of you should leave the Fort.Please.
小卒子,這兒有個洞
Soldier,there"s a hole ahead.
有洞就鑽好了
Just get in.
這是什麼洞?
What kind of hole is this?
救命...
Help!
小卒子,快救我
你醒醒...你沒死吧?
Wake up!Are you dead?
我在什麼地方?
Where am I?
你怎麼不會游水?
Can"t you swim?
我不會游水的
No,I can"t swim.
飛劍
Flying swords!!
你們這些臭八婆,這麼喜歡看就看吧
You bitches!See all you want then!
連那條都沒有了
There goes that one too!
我要帶你們兩個人去見你們的師父
L"m going to take you to your teachers.
讓他們知道你們怎麼傷風敗俗
To show them how you"re giving your Clan a bad name!
不要...大姐我求求你別告訴我師父
I beg you.Please don"t tell my Teacher.
勝敗乃兵家常事,怕什麼?見就見
You win some,you lose some.There"s nothing to be afraid of!
讓我師父知道我拉她褲腰帶
If Teacher finds out I pulled at her pants,
我真變成傷風敗俗了
I will be in big trouble!
拉褲腰帶有什麼關係
Pulling her pants is no big deal!
什麼?
What?
怎麼?
What now?
你別再讓她生氣了
Please don"t be mad.
大姐,你叫我做什麼我就做什麼
L"ll do whatever it takes to make it up to you.
大事化小事,小事化無事,只要沒事就行
Just don"t make this any bigger than it is.
這樣,好,你打他,他打你
Fine.Then slap each other until
打到我的氣順了為止
my nerves are calmed.
你氣順了我的氣可不順
Then my nerves will not be calm!
你們有沒有說過士可殺不可辱,我不打
Haven"t you heard that a man would rather be killed than insulted?
還這麼嘴硬,見你們師父去
Then l"ll bring you to see your teachers.
他們又不是我師父,見就見
Fine with me.They"re not my teachers anyway.
不行...小卒子,你打我好了,打我
No,no!Soldier,why don"t you just slap me?
我不打兄弟的
I don"t hit my buddies.
你別把我當你的兄弟,打我好了,打我
Don"t consider me your buddy.Just do it.
我不打...
I won"t do it.
那我自己打我自己
Then l"ll slap myself.
你這麼沒骨氣,怎麼做掌門?
Have a little backbone!How can you be Chief of a Clan?
我看也做不了
I was planning to give that up anyway.
我頂
Block!
幸虧我法寶沒出齊,否則以為我沒玩意
Good thing I still have a few tricks up my sleeves.
既然冰焰已盡,就是說緣於此
The Flame died.It is fate that we should part.
堡主,我們後會有期
Until we meet again,Countess.
既然緣盡於此,怎麼會後會有期?
If it is fate that we should part,why should we meet again?
冰緣盡情緣了,為什麼還肯出來見我?
If it is fate that we should part,then why did you come out to see me?
我出來不是為了見你
I didn"t come out to see you.
不是為了見我,難道為了打我?
No?Did you come out to fight me then?
姓丁的你說得對
Ting-Yin,you are right.
當日醫病你對我無禮 ,我要一雪當日之恥
You must pay for the other day when you took advantage of me.
無禮 ?你不是消耗過度,神智不清嗎?
Took advantage?Have you lost your mind from over exhaustion?
當日你突然暈倒,我順手相扶這算無禮 ?
The other day you fainted,and I tried to help you!
我丁某只知道非禮 ,你教教我吧
You tell me if that was taking advantage of you.
我...
I...
你...你說
You tell me!
姓丁的,你太狂妄了,我要教訓你
Ting,you"re too arrogant.I must teach you a lesson.
就用兩招來教訓我,太少了吧
Just two moves?That doesn"t make for much of a lesson!
我知道你有事在身,我放你一馬
I know you have important business to tend to.L"ll let you go.
是嗎?
Really?
我留下三招,等你回來再打
L"ll save three moves for your return.
你有膽等我就有膽回來
If you can wait,I will return.
好,我們擊掌為約
Good.Let"s make a pledge!
一真...
Yi-Chen...Yi-Chen...
這樣也好,你就留下照顧你師父吧
That"s fine.You will stay to take care of your teacher then.
你可以出來了
You can come out now.
我早知道你一定跟著我來的
I knew you"d follow me.
你手無寸鐵,發生了事怎麼辦?
You"re not even armed.What do you do if something happens?
你有兩把劍,給我一把防身吧
You have two swords.You can give me one!
這把劍我是留著送給我徒弟的
L"ve been saving this sword for my student.
師父
Teacher!
你不要表錯情,我還沒想收徒弟
Don"t misunderstand me.L"m not taking students yet.
這把劍我暫時借給你用好了
But I can let you borrow this sword for now.
拿去吧
Take it.
也好,總比沒有好
I guess it"s better than nothing.
大俠
Master Ting!
糟了,有人出事了
Oh no,someone is in trouble!
大俠...
Master Ting,Master Ting!
我的臉色是不是很難看
Does my face look terrible?
不是,不是算十分難看
No,not too bad.
我已經封了自己的九大經脈
L"ve tried to slow the poison from spreading,
紙是包不住火的
but I can"t control it much longer.
不怕,我馬上送你去仙堡
Let"s get you back to the Fort right away.
狄明奇,你是不是很想做我徒弟?
Ti Ming-Chi,are you still anxious/to be my student?
叩三個頭你就是我的收弟
Bow to me three times and you"ll be my student.
這把劍永遠屬於你
This sword will belong to you forever!
師父的話你聽不聽?聽
Do you obey your teacher"s orders?Yes.
我要你答應我一件事
I want you to promise me one thing.
如果三天之內到不了仙堡,你就要殺了我
If we don"t make it to the Fort within three days,kill me.
聽見了沒有,殺了我,殺...
Did you hear me?Kill me!Kill,kill,kill!
殺...
Kill...
他...
He...
怎麼你也中毒
Oh,you got poisoned too?
快點叫堡主出來救他
Hurry!Go ask the Countess to come out and save him!
大師,堡主出不出來救他
Abbot,whether the Countess comes out
要看他跟堡主有沒有緣
will depend on his fate.
冰焰盡,情緣了,是仙堡規矩
She abides by the rule of the Flame.
規矩?
Rule?
是的,師父,救你的時候,就是這樣的
Yes,Teacher.It was the same when we brought you here.
住口,你是崑崙派的叛徒,輪不到你說話
Quiet!You"re a Kun-Lun traitor.It is not your place to talk.
冰焰?
The Flame?
不錯
That"s right.
那麼去點,快...
Then hurry up...hurry...hurry.
堡主
Countess!
身為佛門弟子,竟然這麼毫無修養
How can a monk be so contemptuous?
這兒是瑤池仙堡,你以為是崑崙山麼?
You are at the Fort,not at your own Kun-Lun Mountain!
再不叫堡主出來我就不客氣了
Get the Countess now or you will be sorry!
你不客氣,我也不客氣
Try anything and YOU will be sorry!
你們這些女人,閒來沒事做
You women have nothing else better to do
整天躲在這種地方,想出古靈精怪的規矩
than to hide here and make up these ridiculous rules.
我做和尚也是為了你們這些女人
You were the reason I became a Monk!
我不理你們
L"m wasting my breath!
你有膽子就出來
You!Come out if you have any guts at all!
沒膽子就一輩子躲在裡邊算了
Otherwise stay in there forever,
臭八婆
stupid old maid!
曉如,過門就是客,何必強人所難
Hsiao-Yu!We are guests here.We must not impose.
堡主跟我有言在先,說我一定會回來
I had promised the Countess that I would be back.
想不到竟然一語成
I just didn"t know it would be under these circumstances.
師父
Teacher.
徒弟
Student.
師父
Teacher.
你現在是南海門門人
You are now a Nan-Hai student.
我要你執行南海門門規
You must do your duty according to the Nan-Hai Principles.
為了除魔滅妖,大義滅親
"To destroy evil,even your dearest must not be spared."
快點
Do it now!
Quick!
大義滅親,冰焰盡,情緣了,都是放屁
To hell with fate and rules and principles!
看著活人不醫,看著一點火焰做人
We"re letting a man die because of a flame!
去你的冰焰,去你的規矩
To hell with your flame!
你們都是一盤散沙...我不殺...
You all have lost your minds.I won"t do it!I won"t kill!!
別攔著我...
Get out of my way...
還不放手
Get your hand off of me!
你出來了
Lt"s about time!
姬無霜 堡主
Chi Wu-Shuang.Countess.
竭盡所能,聽天由命,你明白嗎?
We try our best and leave the rest to fate.Do you understand?
堡主,你...
Countess,you...
既然一定要發生的事,就讓他發生吧
Just let what"s meant to happen,happen.
什麼事?
What is wrong?
堡主為了醫你元氣大傷
The Countess already used up her energy when healing you.
現在再醫你的朋友,恐怕對她有危險
Now to heal your friend,she is endangering her own life.
丁引,我醫治你朋友,已經耗盡元氣
Ting-Yin,l"ve used up my energy on your friend.
現在,我不夠真氣再治你了
Now I am too weak to help you.
命在醫者手,既然這樣
If that is the way,then so be it.
堡主,你殺我吧
Countess,please kill me.
我是有這個打算
I do plan to.
我明白
I understand.
含笑身犧牲
"I sacrifice my life with no regrets"
一朝了恩仇
"We will meet again in another world"
堡主給我打傷了,快點去救他
l"ve injured the Countess.Help her,quick!
師父 師伯
Teacher!Master Ting!
你沒事吧
Are you all right?
師父 師伯
Teacher!Master Ting!
丁引
Ting-Yin!
師父...
Teacher!Teacher!
你看看你,把他打成這樣
See,see how badly you"ve beaten him!
好吧,你們這兒誰可以做主
All right,who makes decisions here?
好了...沒人做主是不是?我做主了
No one?Then l"ll do it.
從現在開始,他有什麼事,由我來負責
From now on,I will be responsible for him.
放開我...
Let go of me!
你幹什麼?
What are you doing?
你真的想打死他
Do you really want to kill him?
我說過他的事由我負責
I said l"m responsible for him.
放開我...
Let me go!Let me go!Let go...
你放開我
Let go of me...
你先下來,讓我來想辦法,快點下來
You get down first.We"ll figure something else.
放開我...
Let go of me!
你是不是想殺他?
Do you really want him dead?
死和尚,走開
Get lost,you stupid Monk!
你要殺他就先殺我
You"ll have to kill me first!
堡主
Countess.
你們快點走,我要打破銅鏡冰封這兒
You must all go now.L"ve to break the Ice Mirror and freeze this place.
堡主,那你自己怎麼出去?
Countess!How will you get out then?
不能讓丁引出去
Don"t let Ting-Yin get out.
不要管我
Don"t worry about me.Just go.
為什麼不殺他
Why didn"t you kill him?
快點離開仙堡
Get out of the Fort now!
為什麼?為什麼?
Why?Why?
堡主
Countess!
來不及了
Lt"s too late!
師父...
Teacher...Teacher...
都怪你不好
It"s all your fault.
你不帶你師父來就不會連累我師父
If you hadn"t brought Ting-Yin here,my Teacher would be fine.
快救我師父出來...
You"d better get my Teacher out!You get my Teacher out!
整個仙堡都冰封,你們兩個在這兒幹什麼
The Fort is freezing over.What are you two still doing here?
不要管我
Lt"s none of your business!
有血
There"s blood!
你封不住我的
You can"t keep me here!
什麼事
What"s happening?
冰不斷的落下,這裡遲早會冰封住
We"ll be buried alive!
我們盡快走
We better get out!
這兒是仙堡唯一的出口
This is the only way out.
就是這兒
Here!
這個洞我試過了,我不會游水會淹死我的
L"ve tried this hole before.I almost drowned.
我不去,你們去吧,我不去
L"m not doing it again!You two go on ahead.L"m not going!
我們拉他進去
Just drag him with us!
不行,我不去,會淹死我的
No...No.L"ll drown!
救命
Help!
你幹什麼?
What"s the matter?
我從來沒有離開過仙堡
L"ve never left the Fort in my life.
現在我也不知道到哪兒去?
Where shall I go now?
你到哪兒去?我不知道該怎麼說
I don"t know what to tell you.
男兒志在四方
For men,the world is their domain.
你一個女流之輩,不但不懂事整天就會哭
But you are a girl.And all you do is scream and cry.
為了以後日子打算,不如到廟裡去做尼姑
Perhaps you should become a nun.
生活雖然單調,你挺合適的
Life may be a little bland,but it"ll fit you fine.
討厭,你少說兩句行不行?
What?Can"t you just shut up?
我不會說話,想到什麼就說什麼
L"m not good with words,but that"s how I see it.
十五,十六,十七
15,16,17...
你過來幹什麼?
What do you want?
一真,你記不記得,長眉叫我們去天刀峰
Yi-Chen,remember Long Brows asked us to go to Heaven"s Blade Peak
找李亦奇和紫青雙劍
to find Li l-Chi and the Twin Swords.
現在還剩半個月時間,如果再不去找
We have only half a month left.If we don"t hurry,
元神出竅,天下正道人士就會大難臨頭
it will be doomsday for all when the Blood Demon egresses.
仙堡裡的人我都救不了
We couldn"t even save those in the Fort.
你還叫我想辦法救人家
How can we save anyone else?
我本來是個西蜀兵,因為沒法子才當兵
I was originally a soldier from West Zu,but life for a soldier was unbearable.
但求有一天有能人出現來搭救我們
I had hoped that someone would save us from self-destruction.
後來碰到我的師父以為有救
Then I ran into our teachers and thought they were the ones to save us.
沒想到正道人士不但肯團結,做事又遲慢
But the so-called righteous argued endlessly and refused to unite.
現在紫青雙劍又沒找到
The Twin Swords have yet to be found,
我跟師父已經四分五散了
and I have already lost my Teacher.
他們只管自己門派的事
My teacher,like yours,cares only about his own clan.
說是降妖服魔,守正辟邪普救天下
They talked about exorcising the demons and saving the world,
其實是一盤散沙
but they"re just a bowl of loose sand.
如果我們也像他們那樣,別說救他們
If we follow in their footsteps,
就連我們這一代也不能自己救自己
we won"t even be able to save ourselves.
說得對,師父師伯就是不肯團結
You"re right.The Blood Demon got his way
所以才輸給邪魔
because my Teacher and Master Ting refused to work together.
我們不能像他們那樣
We cannot be like them.
那我們現在怎麼辦?
Where shall we go from here?
我們三個人即刻起程,合力上天刀
We"ll go to Heaven"s Blade Peak immediately!
天刀峰?
Heaven"s Blade Peak?
地方這麼大
This place is huge!
還有兩天,去哪兒找嗎?
We have two days left.How do we find Li l-Chi?
是的
Yes.
你們怎麼那麼笨,用嘴
You two are really dumb!Use your mouths!
用嘴
Our mouths!
李亦奇女俠
Lady Li l-Chi!
快走
Run!
豈有此理,用嘴找
Use our mouths!That was a stupid idea!
你看那邊
Look over there!
下面有個入口
There"s an entrance down there!
江湖笑傲,唯我天刀
Heaven"s Blade is fearless and shuns the world!
你們幾個來到這兒,究竟為了什麼事?
What are you all doing here?
難道他就是李亦奇?
Is he Li l-Chi?
你糊塗,李亦奇是女人
Don"t be foolish.Li is a woman.
我問你們的問題還沒有答覆我
You have not answered my question.
一點規矩都不懂
Where are your manners?
你們知不知道剛才幾乎闖入了魔界
Did you know you almost stepped into Evil Territory just now?
這兒就是天地之極神魔交界的地方
This is the border between Good and Evil.
這是神魔交界?
Border?
對了,你怎麼讓人鎖在這兒麼老伯?
By the way,who chained you here,Old Man?
混帳,我不是老伯,我是天刀
Nonsense!L"m not Old Man!L"m Heaven"s Blade!
天下間沒有能鎖得住我
No one in the world can chain down Heaven"s Blade!
是我自己鎖住自己的
I chained myself here.
你明知道這兒是魔界入口
Why did you chain yourself at
為什麼還鎖著自己
the entrance to the Evil Territory?
老伯
Old Man!
你們走開,不用管我
Stay away!I can take care of myself!
天地本為體,但神魔未盡一家
From the beginning of time,the Heavens and Earth were one.
自從盤古開天,混沌以來
But the Gods and Devils were always at war.
神魔鬥爭,已經相生不息
Never-ending wars.
為了這樣,我天刀這兒費思百年
I have been here for over a century,
為了三透個中道理
trying to understand the logic of this.
結果反而被魔界的玄陰之氣所侵
But instead,I was invaded by the Evil Force.
定力日漸消退
My strength is depleting fast.
所以我沒辦法不鎖住自己
That is why I had to chain myself down.
天地間有一個玄陰之氣流沛在宇宙之中
There is an evil force lurking in the universe.
就因為有正氣所在
Because of an equally strong righteous force,
所以才畏縮在地府之中
it stays in the Evil Territory.
玄陰之氣就是天下自毀的魔性根源
This evil force is the basis of all self destruction.
雖然它在魔界裡呼之欲出
Although it stays in the Evil Territory,
但是它還支配著天下邪魔戰禍
it masterminds all evil wars and disasters on earth.
玄陰之氣一朝未滅,天下永無太平
There will never be peace in the world as long as the Evil Force exists.
可惜我天刀年數已長後繼無人
It is unfortunate that l"m old and
只有留守這裡
can merely stand guard here.
如果被邪魔闖入魔界
If any evil is able to get into the Evil Territory and unite with the Evil Force,
它們的千年魔行,只需一朝了
the consequences will be too frightening to even ponder.
難道天下間就沒人能破玄陰之氣嗎?
Is there no one who can destroy his Evil Force?
現今天下正氣鋒芒已衰
The Righteous Force is weakening.
後繼何人未必是紫青雙劍和李亦奇
Even Li l-Chi and the Twin Swords may not be able to succeed.
李亦奇,她現在在哪兒?
Li l-Chi?Where is she?
這兒是神魔交界有玄陰魔極
Since this is the border between the Good and Evil,
當然也會有神城之府
the gods have their bases here too.
她在你們右邊的天外天洞外洞
She is in the Cave Beyond to your right.
我們終於找到她了
We"ve finally found her!
可惜太遲了
It is too late!
太遲了?她已經死了嗎,老伯?
Too late?Is she dead?
混帳,你死了她沒死
Of course not.She will outlive all of you.
我是說想不到我自己的功力退化得那麼多
What I meant was I did not realize my strength has deteriorated so much.
有人進來這麼久,我現在才知道
It is only now that I detected a stranger"s presence.
師父
Teacher!
魔由心生,心生萬象
Evil comes from the heart.
神為魔生,魔為神活
Gods come from devils.
神魔本是一家
Good and evil are one
天下間那有正邪之分
and the same.
玄陰之氣,無上魔法
May the Evil Force live forever.
他想入魔界
He wants to get into the Evil Territory!
有我天刀在這兒你休想踏入魔界一步
You will have to get passed me,Heaven"s Blade,first.
撞到我鼻子了
I hurt my nose!
我們擋住他
Let"s stop him!
七夕劍
Chi Hsi Sword?
不錯,七夕劍
That"s right.
七夕劍是正義之劍,我們似曾相識
Chi-Hsi Sword is a righteous sword,a sword I once knew.
似曾相識?
The sword is the same,
但是人事全非,除非你改邪歸正
but you have changed.Repent!
不知不高地厚
You are too naive!
就算天高地厚我也要扭轉乾坤
Naive or not,I must give it a try!
天下已經夠亂,我不讓你踏入魔界
The world is already full of evil.L"ll not let you into the Evil Territory!
螳臂擋車,不自量力
You obviously don"t know your limits!
你還是這麼硬骨頭
You still insist?
小卒子...
Soldier!!
孺子可教不用怕,有我在這兒
Young man,you have a great potential.Don"t worry.L"m here.
天刀,你的功力悉數耗盡
Heaven"s Blade,your strength is almost all gone.
我勸你還是留著你的殘軀
You"d better save what"s left of your ragged body
回鄉下貽養天年
to live a few more years.
我的殘軀老體?
My ragged body?
正邪相鬥成敗在於克敵意志
The battle between good and evil is a battle of wills.
意志?
Wills?
一個如日方中一個夕陽遲暮,沒有斗的
Your dying will is no match for my rising strength and power!
你怎麼樣了?
Are you all right?
這兒吸力很大,你們可別過來
The magnetic force is very strong over here.Stay away!
你們快走,不走就走不了
Get out of here now before it"s too late!
小卒了...你抓穩了別放手
Soldier...Hold on,don"t let go!
小卒子...
Soldier...Soldier!
Soldier!
小心
Watch out!
一真...
Yi-Chen!
一真,你幹什麼?
Yi-Chen,what are you doing?
我的膽子這麼小,我看也不能做掌門人了
L"ve always been a coward.L"m not fit to be the Chief.
這串佛珠交給你,替我送回崑崙山吧
Here are the beads of the Chief.Please return them to Kun-Lun for me.
那你呢?
Then what about you?
小卒子現在在裡邊,還有機會去救他
Soldier is now inside.There"s still a chance to get him out.
一真,我也跟你去
L"ll go with you!
這怎麼行,如果我們兩個都不能出去
Don"t be silly.If we both can"t get out,
誰去找紫青雙劍?
then who will find the Twin Swords?
那麼我在這兒等你
L"ll wait for you here!
你等我?
Don"t wait.If I make it out alive,l"ll look for you.
出不來的話你等我有什麼用
If I don"t,there"s no use in waiting.
別再猶疑了,分手吧
Don"t hesitate anymore.Go now!
如果你再不走的話,誰也救不了誰,分手
If we both die,we"re no good for anyone!
走吧...
Go...Go!
你還不走?
What are you still waiting for?
小卒子
Soldier!
快去救小卒子,不然他就被吸入魔界了
Hurry and save the boy before he"s sucked into the Evil Territory!
一真...
Yi-Chen!
小卒子
Soldier!
你抓住,讓我拉你過來,抓穩
Grab the beads.Grab it!
小卒子,你放心,現在沒事了
Soldier,don"t worry.We"re safe now.
不過不知道怎樣才能出去
But how do we get out of here?
用我最後一口氣送你們出去
L"ll use my last breath to send you out.
快點抓住你們身邊那條鐵煉
Hold fast onto the chain.
天刀老人為我們而死
Heaven"s Blade sacrificed his life for us.
小卒子
Soldier.
小卒子...你快點上來
Soldier...Come out of there.
我不會游水的,我救不了你,小卒子
I don"t know how to swim.I can"t save you!Soldier!
小卒子...
Soldier...
小卒子,我們逃出魔界了,沒事
Soldier,we got out of the Evil Territory.We"re safe now.
小卒子,你怎麼樣?
Soldier are you alright?
小卒子,你醒醒,你覺得怎樣,小卒子
Soldier...Wake up!Soldier...Answer me!
紫劍?青劍?
The Purple Sword?The Green Sword?
小卒子,你看見沒有?看見了沒有
Soldier,did you see that?
是紫青雙劍
Lt"s the Twin Swords!
那邊還有一個人
Look!And there"s someone over there!
李亦奇?
Li l-Chi?
貧道就是
That"s me.
好了,小卒子我們...
Hooray!We"ve...
小卒子,我們找到李亦奇了
We"ve found Li l-Chi!
怎麼你變成這樣?
Hey,what"s happened to you?
你也是
You too!
李亦奇道長
Lady Li.
長眉的事我知道了
I know all about Long Brows.
所謂遍到英雄千重浪,江山代有才人出
Heroes are born in every generation.
紫青雙劍這一代的主人是你們
The two of you will be the next owners of the Twin Swords.
多謝道長賜劍
Thank you,Lady Li.
天地之氣掌乾坤宇宙
The Twin Swords were cast out of stones from heaven and earth,
紫青雙劍是天地精石所鑄
the universe.They absorbed centuries of Universal Force.
劍由人用,人由心控
The swords are employed by men.And men are controlled by their hearts.
只要天地人三者合一,威力就會無窮無盡
When these forces unite,the Swords are invincible.
但是乾坤陰陽相生相勀
But the two swords must not
所以雙劍不能互相碰撞
touch one another
不然就會造成破壞
or destruction will take place.
輕則用劍者死,重則傷及天地
The swordsman may die
所以會做成萬物俱亡
and the world may be completely devastated.
但是這兩把天地之間最大威力
But the Twin Swords are also
也是在它們合一的時候
most powerful when they unite.
那碰也死,不碰也死,那是什麼意思
So it"s damned if you do and damned if you don"t.
所以我個人也無法三透
This is part of the puzzle I have failed to solve.
我用千里傳音問長眉三透了沒有
I wonder if Long Brows has deciphered it!
長眉
Long Brows.
他們找到了紫青雙劍了
They have found the Twin Swords!
幹什麼?
Wow!
為什麼李亦奇會跟我心意相通
Why am I sharing Li l-Chi"s thoughts?
長眉,為什麼兩劍不能相碰?
Long Brows,when can the Twin Swords touch one another?
兩劍如果要互相碰撞
It is only safe for the two swords to touch each other
一定要用劍者二人心意相通
when the two swordsmen share the same mind.
七星移位快到了
The Big Dipper is shifting
到時候浩天鏡快會失去效力了
and my Sky Mirror will soon lose its power.
那怎麼才是心意相通?
What does it mean by sharing the same mind?
心意相通即說話也會異口同聲
It is when two act in unison.They think and talk simultaneously.
劍由人用,人由心控,兩人心意相通
The swords are employed by men and the men are controlled by their minds.
兩劍就會混成一體,扭轉乾坤天地合一
When the minds are in unison,the two swords become one.
天地合一,在乎兩人心意相通?
So two minds in unison is the key?Heaven and Earth become one Universe?
紫劍為天青劍為地
Purple Sword as Heaven,Green Sword as Earth.
紫青雙劍,天地合一
Purple and Green unite.Heaven and Earth in unison.
李道長...
Lady Li...
師父...
Teacher.
你們兩個不用傷心
The two of you don"t have to worry.
是不是你搞鬼?不是
Did you do this?No...
是我,我把你們合二為一了
It"s me.I have united the three of us into one.
那我們是不是男人?
Are we still men?
當然是,你們不用擔心
Of course.You don"t have to worry.
要天地合一,你們二人必須一心一意
To unite Heaven and Earth,you two must be in unison.
透過我元神,就可以心意相通了
You can achieve this through my essence.
長江後浪推前浪,一代新人換舊人
It is time for me to pass the baton to the next generation.
現在已經七星移位,快去峨嵋山
The Big Dipper will soon begin to shift.
殺元嬰,救長眉
Set off immediately to kill the Blood Demon and rescue Long Brows.
是,師父
Yes,Teacher.
東蜀敗兵,你們聽著
Listen up,soldiers of East Zu!
上次讓你們跑了,今天要你們全軍覆沒
This time we won"t let you get away.We want you all dead.
西蜀敗兵,上次我們故意引你們到三丈澗
Soldiers of West Zu.Last time we lured you to San-Chang Creek.
等了半天也沒有看見你這這班縮頭烏龜
But you cowards never showed up!
糟了,七星開始移位
Oh no,the stars have started shifting!
你們不要打了,看看上面
Stop fighting!Take a look above you!
你們有沒有聽見我說話?
Did you hear me?
西蜀兵,我跟你誓不兩立
West Zu,we"ll fight you to the end!
我們統領
Where is our Commander?
沒統領怎麼打?
How do we do battle without a Commander?
你們的統領被我吊在上面了
Your Commanders are up here!
統領怎麼會吊在上面?
How did the Commanders get up there?
山上的元嬰就快出竅了
The devil is coming!
你們再不走就大難臨頭了
You must get out before it is too late!
她在說什麼?
What is the girl talking about?
你看那邊
Look over there!
小心被他吸進去
Be careful not to get sucked in!
一真,這是什麼妖術?
Yi-Chen,what kind of witchcraft is this?
你們快點跟著我來
Quickly,follow me!
我們快點跟著統領走
Let"s follow our Commander.
飛得這麼快,我們怎麼跟?
We can"t keep up.They"re flying too fast!
是丁引?
Lt"s Ting-Yin!
他阻攔著我們救長眉 不錯
He"s trying to stop us!I know.
糟糕,劍讓他鎖住了
Oh no,he has our swords locked in!
一真,小心 小卒子
Yi-Chen,watch out!Soldier!
無上魔法是你們正道的勀星
You cannot fight with Evil!
一真
Yi-Chen!
天怎麼黑了
Why is it dark all of a sudden?
血魔吸日
The Blood Demon absorbs the rays.
站穩...
Hold on!
我讓你出竅還得了,我不讓你蝕日
I won"t let you egress.There will be no eclipse!
怎麼...
What is going on?
老兄,別壓著我
Man,you are crushing me!
我也被人壓著
L"m being crushed myself!
紫青雙劍怎麼還沒有來?
Why aren"t the Twin Swords here yet?
別推我
Don"t push me!
我沒有推你,是地面斜了
Lt"s not me.It"s an earthquake!
別推...拉住,不要掉下去
Don"t fall off the cliff!Hold on.
站也站不住,怎拉?
I can"t hold on.I can"t even stand!
不要推我...
Don"t push me!
你們一個拉看一個就不會掉下去了
Hold on to one another and you won"t all fall off!
捉住,不然便掉下去
Hold on!Otherwise you will fall down.
下面不要這麼用力
You guys are too heavy down there.
別拉我的腳...
Don"t pull my leg.
我們的劍別讓他鎖住
Don"t let him lock our swords!
我知道,我們運劍成盾
I know.Let"s turn our swords into shields!
魔法無邊,你們是擋不住的
You cannot fight Evil!
小卒子,你在哪兒...
Soldier...Soldier,where are you?
一真,我在這兒
Yi-Chen,l"m over here!
一真,你沒事吧?
Yi-Chen,are you all right?
我沒事
Yes,l"m fine.
我也沒事
L"m fine too.
我現在看不見丁引
I can"t see Ting-Yin,
可是他就在我們兩個中間
but he must be somewhere between us.
如果我們要衝破他的魔陣
To win,we must ambush him
一定要夾攻住他
from both sides.
我不知道你在那兒怎麼跟他打?
I don"t even know where you are,how do we fight?
我們心靈相通,一定能找到交合地點
Our minds are in unison.We"ll find each other.
是嗎?
Really?
現在時間無多,快把紫青雙劍合壁
Time is running out.Unite the Twin words!
好
Okay!
想合壁?
Trying to unite?
一真,他想消耗我們的元氣
Yi-Chen,he"s trying to exhaust our energies.
紫郢青索,你們既然開始合壁
If you try to unite the Twin Swords,
神意一定要相通相連
your minds must be in unison.
不然雙劍一碰就會人劍俱毀
Otherwise,as the swords touch,both you and the swords will be destroyed.
最後關頭不要精神分散,一定要集中
Don"t be distracted at the last critical moment!Concentrate!
你們再不合壁,我受不了
Unite the swords now!I can"t hold it much longer!
一真,剛才因為你心散,精神不集中
Yi-Chen,you got distracted
差點毀了紫青雙劍
and almost destroyed the swords.
小卒子,我明白了,我們快點合壁
Soldier,I understand.Let"s do it now!
好
Right!
又被他阻攔住了
We"re blocked again!
你們正道的末日到了
The Doomsday of the Righteous has arrived!
力不從心,我歷史的任務快完了
I can"t do this anymore.It"s over!
血魔出竅
The Blood Demon egresses!
我無辦法了
I don"t want to see this!
丁引,你中毒太深
Ting-Yin,you have fallen too deep.
我看你我都無能為力了
There is nothing either one of us can do.
留得青山在,一朝了恩仇
We shall be together in another world.
正邪只是一線之分
It"s a fine line between good and evil.
堡主犧牲自我
The Countess sacrificed herself
完成降魔大業,真是可敬可佩
for the sake of the world.That is admirable indeed!
快點合壁
Quick,unite now!
這次你還不死?
This time you"re really finished!
這是什麼...
What"s that?
什麼飛下來?
Something"s flying!
是三個人
Lt"s three people!
晚輩拜見長眉
Greetings to Long Brows.
好,真是遍地英雄千重浪
The world really belongs
江山一代勝一代
to the next generation!
我走了
Here I go.
胖子...我們身在兩地但心在一起
Chubby,even though we are apart,our minds are together.
希望把這個葫蘆交給你的時候
I hope by the time I give you back this water bottle,
普天之下人人心意相通
all minds are in unison,
干伐停息,天下太平
all wars have ended,and the world is at peace.
那就什麼災難都沒了
Then everyone will live happily ever after.